Hi I'm Nancy Frensley, I'm the training manager at the Berkeley East Bay Humane Society.
A lot of times people ask me about various types of enclosures in which they can put their dogs for various reasons the most common type of dog pen is an indoor pen usually and it's called an ex pen or exercise pen.
Most of them are made of wire like this one and once dogs are trained to stay inside them, they don't try to get out.
They are happy, they have freedom of movement, this pen for instance can become much, much larger.
And those of us that go to competitions and take our dogs to compete various places have all trained our dogs to stay inside an indoor enclosure like this.
Sometimes they are just under a canopy.
These are very, very useful for instance if you take your dog to the park for a picnic.
You can house your dog inside a comfortable enclosure like this, temporary and use it for a temporary enclosure inside, so that your dog has room to move around.
When you are house training a dog, especially a small dog, could work well in a small pen like a short pen like this.
When you are house training a puppy, a pen like this is more comfortable then a crate so your puppy learns to go in the crate for short term confinement and in the pen for longer term confinement.
These pens come in a number of different heights and sizes so you can get pens that are very, very tall for larger dogs.
The trick is to do it while you are at home, teach your dog to settle down in the pen by using rewards, little treats, good girl, she's being a very, very good girl there.
She's getting a little treat for lying down and they become quite comfortable inside the pen.
One of the best uses for these pens is when you have a dog and a small child.
This the pen indoors gives your dog a nice safe place to be so a toddler isn't tripping, falling or grabbing at fur and it helps your dog feel safe while getting used to a small child in your home.